J SARATH KUMAR

- 🖈 : BANGALORE, KA, 560016 📱 8498906002 🖾 :sarathkumarj800123@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sarath-kumar-j GitHub: github.com/Sarath-Kumar-J-800123

SUMMARY

Frontend and Backend developer with 4 years of experience. Intend to build a career with leading corporate of Hi-tech environment with committed & dedicated people, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential. I desire to work as a key player and team member in challenging & creative environment

WORK EXPERIENCE

Java Full Stack Developer, PalleTechnologies

Feb 2023 - Present

Bangalore

- Collaborated on the design, development, and deployment of web applications.
- Contributed to front-end development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript frameworks.
- · Assisted in back-end development with Java, Spring, and RESTful APIs.
- Conducted testing, bug fixing, and participated in code reviews.
- Demonstrated proactive problem-solving and a commitment to continuous learning.

Feb 2020 - Jan 2023 Hyderabad

- Instrumentation engineers design, develop, install and maintain equipment to monitor and control machinery.
- They configure automated processes to improve the productivity, reliability and safety of production.
- They might build instruments like: Dynamometers for measuring torque.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Instrumentation

June 2017- July 2019

Sri Venkateswara University

Tirupati

- Control systems for outdoor equipment. System modules for automation technology.
- Sensor technology and optoelectronics (e.g. control and alarm devices)

Bachelor of Science in Maths, Physics and Electrons

July 2014 - April 2017

P V K N Govt College

Chittoor

• power, communication, control, signal processing, embedded systems, robotics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Technologies: JDBC, SERVLETS, JSP, J2EE, Object Oriented Programming
- Framework: Hibernate , Spring , Spring MVC , Spring Boot
- Databases: MySQL
- Interest: Coding, Night Rides

PROJECTS

Human Resource Management System

- **Java:** The core programming language for developing the application logic and user interface.
- **JDBC**: The Java API for connecting and interacting with the database.
- **Relational Database Management System:** MySQL, PostgreSQL, or any other RDBMS for storing student-related data.
- HTML, CSS and JavaScript: For web-based components or web integration, if required.

Ticket Booking System Sign Up

- Implemented secure user authentication and registration functionalities to ensure data privacy and access control.
- Developed an intuitive registration form allowing users to input essential details such as name, email, password and contact information.
- Utilized JDBC to establish a connection with the backend database, storing newly registered user information securely.
- Leveraged JSP to dynamically generate content, enhancing the overall registration experience.